[ SIGHS ]
[ POLICE RADIO CHATTER ]
PIERCE.
WHAT'S UP?
I'M GONNA NEED YOU
TO SIT ON THIS GUY.
OKAY.
YOU KEEP
YOUR MOUTH SHUT.
OKAY.
NOBODY TALKS TO HIM.
NOBODY COMES IN.
ROGER THAT.OH, SHIT.
OH, MAN,
HE'S ONE OF THEM.
DON'T LEAVE.SHUT THE FUCK UP.
THE FUCK, MAN?
WHAT?
YOU WANT TO COME ROUGH?
I COULD BOOK YOUR ASS RIGHT NOW
FOR ASSAULTING A POLICE OFFICER.
THAT'S A YEAR MINIMUM
IN COUNTY, SMART GUY.
I'M SORRY, MAN,
THAT WAS WRONG.
WHY'D YOU RUN?'CAUSE EVERYONE ELSE DID.
IT'S LIKE A --
A REACTION.
"FIVE-O! FIVE-O!"
THAT'S WHAT YOU DO.
YOU RUN.
WE JUST WANTED
TO TALK TO YOU.
YOU DID?
SHIT,
I WISH I HAD KNOWN.
MY RIBS ARE BROKEN,
MAN.
THAT BLACK OFFICER WANTED
TO FUCKING KILL ME.
WHAT'D YOU EXPECT?
HE HEARD THE SHOT,
SAW HIS PARTNER ON THE GROUND.
I DIDN'T DO THAT, MAN.
I SWEAR TO GOD,
I DIDN'T SHOOT HER.
I WAS THERE.
I KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
THEN YOU KNOW
I DIDN'T DO IT.
PUTS ME THE ONLY FRIEND
YOU GOT RIGHT NOW, STOKES.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
TELL ME ABOUT
ARTHUR DELACROIX.
WHO?
PART OF YOUR SKATEBOARD POSSE
BACK IN THE DAY.
THAT'S YOU.
THAT'S YOUR CREW,
RIGHT?
[ LAUGHS ]
OH, MAN.
I WAS -- I WAS LOADED
MOST OF THE TIME BACK THEN.
I DON'T EVEN REMEMBER
THESE GUYS' NAMES,
IF I EVER KNEW THEM.
WHICH ONE'S YOUR BOY?
LET ME ASK THE QUESTIONS.
THIS PICTURE,
WHERE WAS IT TAKEN?
FUCK, MAN, I DON'T REMEMBER.
YOU AND YOUR BOYS EVER SKATE
UP IN LAUREL CANYON?
NO, MAN, WE WERE MIRACLE MILE --
WILSHIRE BOYS.
SOMEBODY TOOK THIS PICTURE,
AND ARTHUR DELACROIX'S FATHER
KNEW YOUR NAME
WHEN HE SAW YOUR FACE.
HE SAID ARTHUR LOOKED UP
TO YOU?
WHERE'D THIS KID LIVE?
OFF WILSHIRE --
CARTHAY CIRCLE.
WELL, THERE YOU GO.
ME TOO --
CARTHAY SQUARE.
THAT MUST BE
HOW HIS POPS KNEW ME.
FROM AROUND THE WAY,
KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
THIS GOOFY KID HERE,
HE WAS FROM CARTHAY, TOO.
I'M PRETTY SURE.
THIS WHO YOU MEAN?
YOU KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM?
NO, MAN.
NO, I MEAN,
I LOST TRACK OF ALL THEM GUYS
AFTER THEY LOCKED MY ASS UP
IN SYLMAR
FOR A WHOLE FUCKING YEAR.
YEAH, WHEN WAS THAT?
'95.
I COME OUT...
ALL MY BOYS ARE SCATTERED.
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
F.I.D.'s HERE
TO TALK TO YOU.
OH, DON'T LEAVE ME, MAN.
[ HANDCUFFS CLICK ]
OW!
♪♪
♪ I GOT A FEELING
AND I CAN'T LET GO ♪
♪ I CAN'T LET GO ♪
♪ I FEEL ♪
[ GLOVE COMPARTMENT OPENS,
CLOSES ]
[ CLICKING,
ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
Bosch:
WHEN I GOT TO THE GARAGE,
I RAN DOWN THE RAMP
TOWARD THE VOICES.
Rosa:
WHAT WERE THEY SAYING?
THERE WAS A LOT OF NOISE.
ECHOES -- I COULDN'T
MAKE IT OUT EXACTLY.
Brasher: STOP RIGHT THERE!
DON'T MOVE. TURN AROUND.
TURN AROUND.
PUT YOUR HANDS ON THE WALL.
AND WHEN YOU
FINALLY CAUGHT UP TO THEM?
LOOK,
IT ALL HAPPENED SO FAST...
WHAT ABOUT
WHEN THE GUN WENT OFF?
[ GUNSHOT ]
AAH!
[ GRUNTS ]
LIKE I SAID,
IT WAS ALL KIND OF BLURRY.
JUST GIVE ME SOME TIME
TO SORT OUT THE DETAILS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
SURE.
MAYBE IT WILL START
TO COME BACK TO YOU.
DID YOU INTERVIEW
OFFICER BRASHER YET?
RHD HAS FIRST DIBS.
WE'LL TALK TO HER
WHEN THEY'RE DONE.
YOU GONNA RING STOKES UP
FOR THOSE?
I HAVEN'T DECIDED.
AH, WON'T NEED TO.
I HEAR RHD IS GONNA HIT HIM
WITH THE FULL MONTY.
FOR WHAT?
ATTEMPT MURDER OF A P.O.,
FOR STARTERS.NOT WHAT HAPPENED.
WELL,
POSSESSION OF A FIREARM.HE WASN'T ARMED.
HE GRABBED BRASHER'S GUN.IS THAT WHAT SHE SAID?
THAT'S WHAT I HEAR.
HEY, STOP PRETENDING
YOU CAN READ.
[ Chuckling ] HEY, HARRY.
HOW YOU DOING, BIG DOG?
BETTER.
AT LEAST THEY TOOK THE TUBE OUT
SO I CAN TALK.
OH, SHIT,
CAN THEY PUT IT BACK?
FUCK YOU.
[ CHUCKLES ]
SORRY THAT SHIT
WENT SIDEWAYS, HARRY.
I'M LOSING MY EDGE.
I'D TURN IN MY BADGE,
BUT THAT FUCKER'S STILL GOT IT.
COULD'VE HAPPENED
TO ANYBODY, CRATE.
WE'LL GET HIM,
AND GET YOUR BADGE BACK, TOO.
WHEN YOU DO, USE MY GUN.
KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
MERRY CHRISTMAS, PALLY.
HM.
"FLEAS NAVI-DOG," HARRY.
"FLEAS NAVI-DOG."
YOU ARE FEELING BETTER.
[ INDISTINCT SINGING]
[ INDISTINCT P.A. ANNOUNCEMENT ]
HOW YOU DOING?
[ CHUCKLES ]
MM.
HOW YOU FEELING?
FLOATING ON AIR.[ CHUCKLES ]
WHAT'D THEY GIVE YOU?[ CHUCKLES ]
SOMETHING REALLY,
REALLY GOOD.
WHAT'S THE DAMAGE?
COUPLE CRACKED RIBS AND A BIG,
DISGUSTING BRUISE.
THEY GONNA LET YOU GO HOME?
[ INHALES DEEPLY ]
I BUMPED MY HEAD
ON THE CONCRETE PRETTY GOOD,
SO THEY WANT
TO KEEP ME OVERNIGHT
IN CASE
I HAVE A CONCUSSION.
SO, ANY VISITORS?
IRVING, UH,
CAME BY FOR A HOT SECOND
WITH CAPTAIN POUNDS.
MM.
MY DAD IS COMING
IN THE MORNING.
HE'S TOTALLY FREAKED OUT.
HE WANTS ME TO QUIT
AND JUST...
WHAT'D YOU TELL HIM?
PFFT, HELL NO.
JUST WHEN I'M ABOUT
TO GET A MEDAL?
[ CHUCKLES ]
HOW ABOUT ROBBERY HOMICIDE?
UH, YEAH,
THEY POPPED IN.
SAID THEY'D BE BACK
WHEN MY REP WAS PRESENT.
YOU NEED TO THINK ABOUT
WHAT YOU'RE GONNA SAY
BEFORE THEY
LOCK YOUR STORY DOWN.
YEAH.
I'LL JUST TELL THEM AGAIN
WHAT I TOLD THEM TONIGHT.
WHICH WAS...?
ASSHOLE WENT
FOR MY FUCKING GUN.
IT WENT OFF.
I'M LUCKY
I WAS WEARING MY VEST.
[ CANE CLACKING ]
OH!
DAVID!
DAVID.[ WHISTLE BLOWS ]
DAVID.Waits: MA?!
[ CRYING ]
MA?
OH, MA,
WHAT'D YOU DO?
DAVID...
WHAT DID YOU DO?
ARE YOU OKAY?
I'M SORRY.
I'M SO SORRY.
I JUST WANTED TO GO
TO THE BATHROOM.
IT'S OKAY.
ARE YOU HURT?
I DON'T KNOW.
OKAY, COME ON.
LET ME HELP YOU UP.
I'M SO EMBARRASSED.
IT'S OKAY.
DON'T BE.
HERE WE GO.
THERE YOU GO.
HOLD ON, NOW.
OH, WHAT WOULD I DO
WITHOUT YOU, HUH?
OKAY, YEAH.
O'Shea: IN CLOSING,
I'D LIKE TO CONVEY
TO THE GOOD PEOPLE
OF LOS ANGELES
THAT THIS RENEWED SENSE
OF MISSION
AND TEAMWORK
BETWEEN MY OFFICE AND LAPD
SHOULD HELP US ALL
SLEEP MORE SOUNDLY
THIS HOLIDAY SEASON.
CHIEF?
THE APPREHENSION
OF RAYNARD WAITS
REMAINS OUR TOP PRIORITY.
AND WE ARE DEVOTING
EVERY RESOURCE
TO ACHIEVING THAT TASK
AS EXPEDIENTLY AS POSSIBLE.
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
BUT WE, AS LOS ANGELES...
TURNED OUT GOOD,
CHIEF.
MORNING SHOWS
ALL CARRIED IT LIVE.
I THINK
WE GOT THE MESSAGE OUT.
NO MORE FINGER-POINTING.
NO MORE LAYING OF BLAME.
ALL HANDS ON DECK
TILL THIS IS OVER.
YES, SIR.
THAT CAME THROUGH
LOUD AND CLEAR.
NOW WE JUST HAVE TO CATCH
THIS LITTLE MOTHERFUCKER...
BEFORE HE
BRINGS US ALL DOWN.
THE ONE DAY OF THE YEAR
THAT I GO IN LATE TO WORK.
AM I INTERRUPTING?
WELL, MM,
AS A MATTER OF FACT...
WE ARE WRAPPING PRESENTS.
CHRISTMAS.
IT'S TOMORROW.
IT IS?
MM-HMM.
HI, HARRY.HEY, LEESE.
ONE OF THOSE FOR ME?
YEAH, THE FRUITCAKE.MM, NICE.
SAME ONE I GAVE YOU GUYS
LAST YEAR?
[ CHUCKLES ]YOU WANT A CUP
OF COFFEE?
SO, WHAT IS SO IMPORTANT
THAT IT COULDN'T WAIT
UNTIL I GOT INTO THE OFFICE?
[ SIGHS ]
BRASHER GAVE RHD
A PRELIMINARY STATEMENT.
[ SIGHS ]
SAID STOKES GRABBED HER GUN.
ALL RIGHT,
ISN'T THAT WHAT HAPPENED?NOT WHAT I SAW.
OH, SHIT.
HARRY,
DON'T TELL ME THIS.
STOKES' HANDS
WERE ON THE WALL.
FUCK!I MEAN, I CAN'T SWEAR TO IT.
COULDN'T SEE CLEARLY.
I THINK SHE TRIED TO CUFF HIM
AND HER GUN WENT OFF.
WELL, IT'S NOT GREAT,
BUT SHIT HAPPENS.
THAT WOULD BE
HER THIRD UNSAT.
OH, SHIT.
SO THAT'S WHY
SHE'S GOT TO PUT IT ON STOKES.
LOOKING TO SAVE HER JOB.
EXCEPT
YOU WON'T CORROBORATE.
NOT THAT I'M ASKING YOU TO.
I MEAN, EITHER WAY SHE'S DONE
IF SHE GIVES A FALSE STATEMENT.
YOU THINK YOU CAN PERSUADE HER
TO DO THE RIGHT THING?
I CAN TRY.
WHAT ABOUT STOKES?
I SHOULD CUT HIM LOOSE.
AT LEAST WAIT
UNTIL TOMORROW.
FEWER OF BRASHER'S
FELLOW OFFICERS AROUND
TO SEE IT GO DOWN.
ALSO GIVES YOU MORE
TIME TO GET BRASHER
TO CHANGE HER STORY.
YEAH, AND IT'S A NICE GESTURE,
WITH THE HOLIDAYS AND ALL.
EXACTLY.
WOMAN: Cable's included,
of course.
GREAT.
THAT'S GREAT.
SHE LOVES HER PROGRAMS,
YOU KNOW?
We have live entertainment
on weekends and holidays,
and we offer non-denominational
services on Sundays.
WELL, THAT -- THAT SOUNDS NICE
AND LOVELY.
UM, HOW MUCH
DOES ALL THIS COST?
Depends on the plan --
what add-ons you select,
the room type.
UH, THE BASIC?
HOW --
HOW MUCH IS THE BASIC?
Medicare would cover
a substantial portion.
GOOD.
Bring your mother in,
Mr. Martinez.
See the grounds,
meet the staff.
DAVID?
Mr. Martinez?
DAVID!
Mr. Martinez,
are you there?
COULD YOU TURN THIS OFF?
...SERIAL KILLER RAYNARD WAITS.
FAMILY MEMBERS
OF LOUIS ESCOBAR, THE DEPU--
WH-WHAT --
I WAS LISTENING TO THAT.
YOU'RE READING.
WELL, I'M TRYING.
WHEN ARE YOU GOING TO PICK UP
MY NEW GLASSES, DAVID?
MA, IT'S A SPECIAL ORDER,
YOUR PRESCRIPTION.
THEY PROMISED
THE DAY AFTER CHRISTMAS.
[ SIGHS ]
ALL RIGHT. FUDGE.
WHAT ARE YOU READING?
I'M BRUSHING UP
ON MY FRENCH GRAMMAR.
MM.
THAT SOUNDS INTERESTING.
DON'T BE SMART.
YOU KNOW, I NEVER UNDERSTOOD
YOUR LACK OF INTEREST.
I MEAN,
YOU COULD HAVE BEEN FLUENT.
DON'T YOU ALREADY KNOW
THIS STUFF IN YOUR SLEEP?
BUT I NEVER TIRE OF IT.
OU SONT MES LUNETTES?
I SAID, MA,
THE DAY AFTER CHRISTMAS.
[ GASPS ]
YOU REMEMBER.
EH.
[ SPEAKS FRENCH ]
HEY.
HOW YOU FEELING?
SORE AS SHIT.
COFFEE?
JUST MADE FRESH.
NO, THANKS.
I'M COFFEE'D OUT.
IT'S NICE OUT HERE.
YEAH.
YOU EVER THINK YOU'D WANT
TO WORK PACIFIC?
SWEET COMMUTE.
BUT NAH.
I LIKE HOLLYWEIRD --
ALWAYS JUMPING.
YEAH.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I KNEW THIS P-2, WILLIAMS,
LOVED WORKING HOLLYWOOD.
YOU KNOW, THE JUICE.
ONE DAY, HE PULLS OVER
THIS CORVETTE, EXPIRED TAG.
GUY BOOKS, CHASE IS ON.
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
SO, WILLIAMS TAKES IT OVER
THREE DIVISIONS,
ALL THE WAY OUT HERE
INTO VENICE.
BY THE TIME IT'S OVER,
HE'S PUMPED,
HE'S PISSED,
HE'S READY TO KICK ASS.
YANKS THE GUY OUT,
THROWS HIM OVER THE HOOD,
TRIES TO CUFF HIM.
BANG!
SHOOTS OUT THE FRONT TIRE
OF THE VETTE.
SCARED THE SHIT
OUT OF BOTH OF THEM.
LOVE IT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THING IS, WILLIAMS,
HE WAS SO AMPED,
THOUGHT HE'D PULLED HIS CUFFS,
NOT HIS GUN.
YOU COME ALL THIS WAY
TO TELL ME THAT STORY?
I CAME OUT HERE TO TELL YOU
ACCIDENTS HAPPEN,
AND I DON'T WANT YOU
TO HURT YOURSELF
WITH A STATEMENT
THAT'S NOT ACCURATE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN NOT ACCURATE?
YOU WERE THERE.
YOU'RE GONNA BACK ME,
RIGHT, HARRY?
RIGHT?
GOD DAMN IT, JULIA.
THAT'S NOT WHAT HAPPENED.
HE DIDN'T GO
FOR YOUR GUN.
HIS HANDS WERE
ON THE WALL.
THAT'S WHAT I SAW.
THAT'S WHAT I'LL SAY.
YOU'RE GONNA BACK
A DIRTBAG OVER ME?
THAT'S NOT WHAT
THIS IS ABOUT.
STOKES IS A STREET STAIN.
IF HE DOESN'T GO DOWN
FOR THIS,
HE'S GONNA GO DOWN
FOR SOMETHING ELSE EVENTUALLY,
AND HURT SOMEBODY ELSE.
FUCK YOU, HARRY.
YOU'RE
A FUCKING HYPOCRITE.
I HEARD OFFICER BRASHER SHOUTING
COMMANDS TO THE SUSPECT.
WHAT WAS SHE YELLING?
"STOP." "DON'T MOVE."
LIKE THAT.
I RAN DOWN THE RAMP
TOWARDS THE VOICES,
SAW THEM
ON THE LOWER LEVEL.
WHAT DID YOU SEE?
Brasher: STOP RIGHT THERE!
DON'T MOVE.
TURN AROUND,
PUT YOUR HANDS ON THE WALL.
TURN AROUND!SUSPECT HAD ASSUMED
THE POSITION,
HANDS AGAINST THE WALL.
OFFICER BRASHER
WAS BEHIND HIM.
WHAT HAPPENED NEXT.
I WAS MAKING MY WAY
AROUND A VEHICLE
TO GET OVER TO THEM
WHEN I HEARD THE SHOT.
DID YOU SEE OFFICER BRASHER
DRAW HER WEAPON?
I DID NOT.
FROM MY VANTAGE POINT,
I COULD ONLY INFER
FROM HER MOVEMENTS
THAT'S WHAT SHE WAS DOING.
AT THAT MOMENT,
WHEN YOU HEARD THE GUNSHOT,
WERE THE SUSPECT'S HANDS
STILL ON THE WALL?
[ GUNSHOT ][ GROANS ]
YES.
BOTH HANDS?
BOTH HANDS.
ON THE WALL.
[ SNORING SOFTLY ]
Waits: HEY, BUDDY.
WHAT ARE YOU DRINKING?
WANT SOME?
LAPD.
OH, FUCK ME.
I'M AFRAID I'M GONNA
HAVE TO WRITE YOU UP FOR THIS.
PUBLIC DRINKING,
OPEN CONTAINER.
[ SCOFFS ]
COME ON, OFFICER.
REALLY?
REALLY.
LET ME SEE YOUR I.D.
I'M A HALF A BLOCK AWAY
FROM MY APARTMENT.
WHAT IF I JUST
POURED IT OUT?
TOO LATE FOR THAT.
HERE.
HAVE A SEAT
WHILE I WRITE YOU UP.
CLOSE THE DOOR.
THIS SUCKS.
WHY AREN'T YOU
IN A POLICE CAR?
'CAUSE IT'S
AN UNDERCOVER OPERATION.
LET ME SEE YOUR I.D.
WHY IS LAPD RUNNING
AN UNDERCOVER OPERATION --
FUCK!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?![ SIREN WAILS ]
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
OHH!
MOTHERFUCKER!
[ GRUNTING ]
FUCK YOU, MOTHERFUCKER!
[ SCREAMS ]
ALL THERE?
YEAH, LOOKS LIKE IT.SIGN HERE.
OKAY.[ DOOR LOCK BUZZES ]
[ SIGHS ]
THIS AGAIN?
REMEMBER ANY NAMES?
SHIT.
YOU OWE ME A SOLID.
YOU TAKE ANOTHER LOOK
OR I'LL PUT YOU BACK IN THE CAN.
KEVIN...GRANDERSEN?
ANDERSEN, MAYBE?
THIS IS, UH,
TOM...PARKER.
T-TOM PARKER,
I'M PRETTY SURE.
MERRY CHRISTMAS, STOKES.
CAN'T SAY
I NEVER GAVE YOU ANYTHING.
OH, WHATEVER.WHERE YOU GOING?
OUT THE FRONT,
FOR YOUR OWN PROTECTION.
[ CHOIR SINGING "SILENT NIGHT"]
ISN'T THIS PRETTY?
OH, I JUST LOVE
THESE BOYS' VOICES, DON'T YOU?
YEAH, MA.
BEAUTIFUL.
YEAH, BEAUTIFUL VOICES.
LIKE ANGELS.
COMME DE BEAUX ANGES.
MM-HMM.
MAKES ME FEEL
ALL CHRISTMAS-Y INSIDE.
OH, I JUST LOVE CHRISTMAS.
DON'T YOU?
MM.
YEAH, I JUST LOVE IT.
J'ADORE NOEL.
J'ADORE LES VACANCES.
OH!
[ SIGHS ]
[ INHALES DEEPLY ]
OOH, WHAT DID I MISS?
UH, BEDFORD FALLS
IS GOING ALL TO HELL
WITHOUT GEORGE BAILEY.
OH...
HAVE ANOTHER PIECE OF PIE.
IT SHOULDN'T GO TO WASTE.
NO, MA, I'M STUFFED.[ STAMMERS ]
DO YOU WANT TO WATCH
THE REST OF THE MOVIE?
I-I KNOW HOW IT TURNS OUT.
I'M GONNA GO OUT
FOR A LITTLE WHILE, MA.
SEE SOME FRIENDS.
YOU'RE OKAY
TILL I GET BACK, RIGHT?
I'M FINE.
TAKE THE FUCKING PIE.
MA.
GO ON.
WISH YOUR FRIENDS
A MERRY CHRISTMAS FOR ME.
I WILL.
AND DON'T STAY OUT
TOO LATE.
I WON'T.
I'LL LOCK THE BACK DOOR.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
JOYEUX NOEL.
JOYEUX FETES.
RIGHT, MA.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
WAS EXPECTING I'D FIND YOU HERE,
DETECTIVE.
ANY PROGRESS?
BACK TO SQUARE ONE,
MORE OR LESS.
RUNNING DOWN
A COUPLE OF NAMES.
WHAT BRINGS YOU IN
ON CHRISTMAS DAY?
WAITS TRIED TO ABDUCT SOMEONE
EARLY THIS MORNING.
I HEARD.
ANY LEADS?
WE'RE WORKING IT.
I UNDERSTAND YOU RELEASED
THIS JOHN STOKES CHARACTER.
I MADE THE DETERMINATION
THE CASE DIDN'T WARRANT
SEEKING THE CHARGES.
A SUSPECT
IN AN OFFICER-INVOLVED SHOOTING?
I DID THE LAPD A FAVOR.
AND HOW IS THAT?
BY NOT PUTTING THE DEPARTMENT
IN A SITUATION
WHERE THE D.A.'s OFFICE
HAD TO WEIGH
CONFLICTING TESTIMONY
OF TWO
OF ITS OFFICERS.
YOU TALKING ABOUT
OFFICER BRASHER'S
VERSION OF EVENTS
VERSUS YOURS?
I DIDN'T THINK
ANY OF US WANTED
THAT DISCREPANCY
TO SHOW UP IN THE MEDIA.
I AGREE.
I'M ASSIGNING YOU
TO THE WAITS CASE, BOSCH --
INDEPENDENT
OF THE TASK FORCE.
I'VE GOT A TERRIFIED CITY,
AND THE TASK FORCE
HAS COME UP WITH NOTHING.
I NEED RESULTS,
DETECTIVE.
SO, YOU DO
WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO.
YOU REPORT TO ME.
MY DIRECT LINE, 24/7.
WHAT ABOUT POUNDS?
YOU LET ME
WORRY ABOUT POUNDS.
AND ARTHUR DELACROIX?
OH, KEEP WORKING IT.
AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED,
BOTH CASES ARE CONNECTED
UNTIL YOU CAN PROVE
BEYOND A DOUBT
WAITS DIDN'T KILL
THAT BOY.
[ KEYS JINGLE ]
[ PAPERS RUSTLE ]
[ SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE]
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
ANYTHING ELSE?
THANK YOU, NO.
MERRY CHRISTMAS, HARRY.
MERRY CHRISTMAS TO YOU.
[ CELLPHONE RINGS, BEEPS ]
BOSCH.
ELEANOR: Hey, it's me.
Where are you?
ON MY WAY TO THE HOMICIDE
DETECTIVES' CHRISTMAS PARTY.
[ Scoffs ]
Sure you are.
MERRY CHRISTMAS,
BY THE WAY.
That's right.
So it is.
I was wondering if you were
ever gonna call your daughter
to wish her
a merry Christmas.
I WAS WAITING
UNTIL AFTER DINNER.
I DIDN'T WANT TO INTERRUPT
ANYTHING THAT YOU GUYS
MIGHT HAVE GOING --
It's your father.
MADDIE:
Merry Christmas, Harry.
HEY.
MERRY CHRISTMAS, HONEY,
HOW ARE YOU?
Uh, okay.
When are you coming back?
SOON AS I CAN.
I'M SO SORRY.
I KNOW I PROMISED.
I'M JUST TOTALLY SQUEEZED OUT
WITH THESE CASES.
That's okay.
SO, LISTEN, I GOT AN IDEA.
I WAS THINKING
THAT MAYBE YOU COULD
COME DOWN AND VISIT ME
IN L.A. SOMETIME.
Really?
That would be
so fricking cool.
YEAH, WE COULD DO A RIDE-ALONG,
GO TO THE ACADEMY.
GO TO THE SHOOTING RANGE.
Awesome.
I MEAN, WE NEED TO RUN IT
BY YOUR MOM FIRST.
SEE WHAT SHE THINKS,
CHECK YOUR SCHOOL SCHEDULE.
MAYBE SPRING BREAK.
[ Call waiting beeps ]
MADDIE,
I GOT TO TAKE THIS CALL.
IT'S -- IT'S WORK.
I'LL CALL YOU BACK LATER, OKAY?
Okay.
LOVE YOU.
I love you, too.
BYE.
Bye.
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
BOSCH.
WAITS:
I just want you to know
I'M HAVING A WONDERFUL HOLIDAY
WITH LOVED ONES.
And I hope
you're having the same.
YOU KNOW, WAITS,
TONIGHT WOULD BE A GOOD NIGHT
TO TURN YOURSELF IN.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
I'd say
YOU'RE SELLING ME
A CHRISTMAS CON JOB.
I'M TRYING TO BRING
THIS THING TO AN END
WITH YOU STILL ALIVE.
COME ON.
I THINK WE KNOW HOW THIS ENDS.
YOU AND ME, HARRY --
DOGS
FROM THE SAME KENNEL.
I kill people.
YOUKILL PEOPLE.
DOESN'T HAVE TO COME
TO THAT.
WE COULD MEET.
YOU PICK THE PLACE.
[ CELLPHONE CLATTERS ]
[ ENGINE TURNS OVER ]
THIS IS DETECTIVE HARRY BOSCH,
HOLLYWOOD HOMICIDE.
NEED ASSISTANCE
PINGING A CELL.
MAN:
Hold on, Detective.
I'll need information
for the affidavit.
THERE'S NO TIME
FOR A COURT ORDER.
THIS IS FOR THE WAITS
SERIAL-MURDER CASE.
EXIGENT CIRCUMSTANCES.
YOU CAN CONTACT
DEPUTY CHIEF IRVING'S OFFICE
IF YOU NEED TO.
[ TIRES SQUEAL ]
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]BOSCH.
MAN: Detective,
we traced that phone --
Glendale Boulevard
between Fletcher Drive
and Waterloo Street,
Silver Lake District.
THANKS.
[ SIREN WAILING ]
[ TIRES SCREECH ]
[ INDISTINCT TALKING ]
SAYS HE FOUND IT IN THE STREET
NEXT TO THE CURB.
KICK THE KID.
HE'S GOT NOTHING TO DO
WITH THIS.
[ SIREN WAILS IN DISTANCE ]
[ INDISTINCT TALKING ]
Edgar: ALL THESE BONES
ARE RIGHT UNDER THE STREETS
OF PARIS.
WHO KNEW?
SO, WHAT YOU THINKING
ABOUT THESE SNAPS?
THEY LOOK RECENT.
MY GUESS IS WAITS
PROBABLY TRAVELED OVERSEAS
AT SOME POINT.
HEY, KIZ, ANY LUCK
WITH THAT PASSPORT CHECK?
NOTHING.
IF WAITS EVER WENT TO FRANCE,
IT WAS UNDER ANOTHER NAME.
OKAY, THANKS.[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
BOSCH.
HEY.
WHEN'D YOU GET IN?THIS MORNING.
THIS IS FROM MADDIE.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
I WANTED TO BE THERE.
YET YOU WEREN'T.
CAME ALL THIS WAY
TO BUST MY BALLS?
[ SCOFFS ]
DON'T FLATTER YOURSELF.
I CAME HERE TO PLAY CARDS.
BEL-AIR FAT CAT HEARD
I WAS KILLING WHALES IN VEGAS.
WANTS TO TRY
TO TAKE ME DOWN.[ SCOFFS ] IS HE IN TROUBLE.
"PREDNISONE."
OH, NO.
OH, NO, D-D-DAVID?
DAVID?
[ WHISTLE BLOWS ]
DAVID!
WHAT, MA?
WHAT? WHAT?
WHAT IS IT?
I-I -- I'M OUT
OF MY FUCKING PREDNISONE.
MA!
WELL, I'M SORRY,
BUT I AM.
WELL, WHAT DO YOU WANT ME
TO DO?
WELL, WOULD YOU --
WOULD YOU BE A DEAR
AND GO GET IT REFILLED
FOR ME, PLEASE?
PLEASE.
S'IL TE PLAîT?
YEAH, SURE.
SURE.
VITE!
OKAY, VITE!
VITE.
Eleanor: "ARRêTE! C'EST
ICI L'EMPIRE DE LA MORT."
I'VE BEEN
TO THE PARIS CATACOMBS.
AT THE ENTRANCE
IS THIS WARNING --
"STOP, HERE IS THE EMPIRE
OF DEATH."
FOUND THIS BOOK
IN WAITS' APARTMENT.
THESE PHOTOS WERE FOUND
AT THIS PAGE.
THE SEVEN
OTHER PRESUMED VICTIMS,
NO BODIES HAVE BEEN FOUND?CORRECT.
MAYBE HE KEPT THEM.
HE COULD BE CREATING HIS OWN
CATACOMB USING THE BONES.
IS HE
STILL CALLING YOU?
YEP.
HE SEES YOU AS A FRIEND,
ADVERSARY, BROTHER.
"DOGS FROM THE SAME KENNEL."
THAT'S WHAT HE SAID.
IT'S RISKY, CALLING YOU.
HE GETS OFF ON IT.
YOU COULD USE THAT.WELL, I'M TRYING.
SO FAR, I CAN'T GET HIM
TO MAKE A MISTAKE,
GIVE ANYTHING AWAY.
PLAY TO HIS VANITY,
CALL HIM OUT --
NOTHING SEEMS
TO MAKE HIM SLIP.
MAYBE YOU NEED
TO WORK UP A SCRIPT
FOR THE NEXT TIME
HE CALLS.
I ASSUME YOU HAVE A PROFILER
FROM BEHAVIORAL SCIENCES
WORKING ON THIS?TASK FORCE DOES.
WHAT DO I NEED THEM FOR?
I GOT THE BEST RIGHT HERE.
HARRY, I TOLD YOU.
I'M STRICTLY
A CARD PLAYER NOW.
AND I'VE GOT TO GO.
ARE YOU GONNA OPEN
MADDIE'S PRESENT?
SHE HAD IT CUSTOM-MADE
FOR YOU.
SWEET.
REALLY SWEET.
[ CHRISTMAS MUSIC PLAYING]
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATION ]
Bosch:
WE'RE GOING IN THERE, WAITS.
REMEMBER WHAT
WE TALKED ABOUT BEFORE.
Waits: I KNOW.
PUT ME IN THE TRUNK,
AND I'LL NEVER SEE
THE LIGHT OF DAY AGAIN.
JERRY, WHAT'S THAT?
WHAT?
ON YOUR COMPUTER.
THE WAITS VIDEO
FROM THE FIELD TRIP VAN RIDE.
PLAY IT BACK.
WE'RE GOING
IN THERE, WAITS.
REMEMBER WHAT
WE TALKED ABOUT BEFORE.
I KNOW.
PUT ME IN THE TRUNK,
AND I'LL NEVER SEE
THE LIGHT OF DAY AGAIN.
THE TRUNK.
WHAT TRUNK?
SHIT,
WE NEED A WARRANT.
FOR A TRUNK?
WHAT'S GOING ON, HARRY?
I MISSED IT.
TRUNK IS A ROOM
WHERE THEY PUNISH KIDS.
I THINK WAITS
MIGHT HAVE BEEN HERE, TOO.
THAT'S THE CONNECTION
HE'S BEEN TALKING ABOUT.
THE THING WE HAVE IN COMMON --
McCLAREN YOUTH HALL.
WAITS' DRIVER'S LICENSE
SAYS HE'S 43.
SO LET'S ASSUME
HE'S SOMEWHERE NEAR THAT AGE,
GIVE OR TAKE A FEW YEARS.
SO, WE WANT RECORD
OF NAMES...
1970 TO 1990 TO BE SAFE.
HE'LL BE
IN THERE SOMEWHERE.
I'LL BE IN THERE,
TOO.
[ SCHOOL BELL RINGS ][ INDISTINCT TALKING ]
YOU WANT THE NAME AND FILE
OF EVERY BOY
THAT WENT THROUGH HERE
OVER A 20-YEAR PERIOD?
WE'RE ONLY LOOKING
FOR ONE.
ONCE WE FIND IT,
YOU'LL GET IT ALL BACK.YOU HAVE A TRUCK?
EXCUSE ME?
THE '70s AND '80s,
ALL LONG BEFORE
WE WENT DIGITAL.
WE'RE TALKING HARD COPIES,
THOUSANDS OF THEM.
DOZENS AND DOZENS
OF FILE BOXES.
DO WHATEVER
YOU HAVE TO DO.
[ Ringing ]
Deputy Chief Irving.
YOU SAID IF I NEEDED ANYTHING
TO CALL YOU.
What do you need,
Detective?
A VAN, MAYBE A TRUCK.
SOME PEOPLE
TO CARRY SOME BOXES, ASAP.
Text me the address.
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
[ OXYGEN TANK HISSING ]
HARRY, EACH KID WAS LISTED
BY YEAR OF ARRIVAL.
ACROSS 20 YEARS,
THAT'S MAYBE 8,000 FILES.
THERE WERE 300 BEDS HERE.
KIDS WERE MOVED IN AND OUT
ALL THE TIME.NOT ALL OF THEM.
SOME OF THEM
WERE HERE FOR YEARS.
ANYWAYS,
JUST THE WHITE KIDS.
CUTS THE WORK IN HALF.
PULL IN THE TASK FORCE,
GET THROUGH IT ALL IN A DAY.
TWO AT THE MOST.
[ ECHOING SCREAMS ]
WE DON'T USE
THAT ROOM ANYMORE.
DRACONIAN PRACTICES ARE THINGS
OF THE PAST, DETECTIVE.
WHY YOU STILL GOT
A MATTRESS IN THERE?
JUST IN CASE?
I WOULD APPRECIATE IT,
DETECTIVE,
IF YOU WOULD CONFINE YOURSELF
TO THE AREA OF THE STORAGE ROOM.
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING.
I'M FROM HERE.
THIS IS WHERE I GREW UP.
AND IF IT WAS UP TO ME,
I'D BURN THIS WHOLE PLACE
TO THE GROUND.
Man: YOU LITTLE SHIT!
SON OF A WHORE!
SON OF A BITCH.
HUH?! HUH?!
WHERE'S THE BOX FROM '78?
WILLEFORD, WHERE'S '78?
UH...RIGHT HERE.
[ MUMBLING ]
WHAT ARE YOU,
SHERLOCK HOLMES?
WE PULL 53 BOXES
OUT OF THERE,
YOU JUST REACH INTO ONE
AND FIND WAITS' FILE?
NOT HIS FILE.
OH.
QU'EST-CE QUE C'EST?
DAVID, WHERE ARE YOU?
OU ES-TU?
OH, OU ES-TU,DAVID?
I'M RIGHT HERE, MA.
[ GASPS ]
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
I'VE BEEN RIGHT HERE,
JUST WATCHING YOU SLEEP.
OH!
YOU SHOULD HAVE WOKEN ME.
I'LL BE UP ALL NIGHT.
DID YOU --
DID YOU GO TO THE PHARMACY?
YEAH, I WENT.
BUT I-I-I DIDN'T GET
THE PREDNISONE.
WELL, WHY -- WHY NOT?
WERE THEY OUT OF IT?
I MEAN,
I NEED MY MEDICATION.
NO, I GOT YOU
SOMETHING BETTER.
A LOT BETTER, I THINK.
WELL, WHAT?
I MEAN, THE DOCTOR
PRESCRIBED PREDNISONE.
MA...
I-I HOPE I HAVEN'T BEEN
A DISAPPOINTMENT TO YOU
IN ANY WAY.
OF -- OF COURSE NOT.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
I'VE ALWAYS TRIED MY BEST
TO TAKE CARE OF YOU.
YOU KNOW THAT, RIGHT?
OH, OF COURSE I DO.
YOU ARE THE GOOD SON.
LE BON FILS.
EVER SINCE YOU CAME
TO LIVE WITH US.
I DON'T KNOW
WHERE I WOULD BE
IF YOU WEREN'T TAKING CARE
OF ME.
IS THERE SOMETHING WRONG?
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
WHO EVER REALLY CARED ABOUT ME.
MY WHOLE LIFE.
YOU PULLED ME OUT
OF THE FIRE.
I LOVE YOU, MA.
I LOVE YOU, TOO, SON.
[ CHUCKLES ]
GIVE ME A KISS.
OH, NO, DAVID,
I DON'T LIKE BEING THIS LOW.
PROP ME BACK UP.
[ SPEAKS FRENCH ]
HUH?
NO, PUT THAT BEHIND ME.
[ SPEAKS FRENCH ]
DAVID, NO.
[ MUFFLED GRUNTING ]
[ SPEAKS FRENCH ]
JE T'AIME.
[ GRUNTING STOPS ]